kingston.ac.uk 2019-04-17

# Privacy policy - Kingston University London

## **Data protection at Kingston University**

Kingston University recognises the value of the personal data that we process and the need to collect, use and dispose of it appropriately and securely. The University endeavours to comply with the principles set out in the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) and the Data Protection Act 2018 and aims to inform, as transparently as possible, enquirers, applicants, students, staff, alumni and members of the public about the purposes for which their personal data may be processed.  

Our website privacy notice and cookie statement is below, but you can find out about how we manage personal data through our other subject-specific data protection policies and privacy notices, which are available online:

  * Data Protection Policy

  * Data Protection Privacy Notice for Staff[ ](https://www.kingston.ac.uk/aboutkingstonuniversity/howtheuniversityworks/policiesandregulations/documents/privacy-notice-staff.pdf)

  * Data Protection Privacy Notice for Alumni and Friends

  * Data Protection Privacy Notice for Enquirers, Applicants, Students and Alumni

  * Retention policy

  * Retention schedule

  * Subject Access Request form 

## **What is this privacy notice about?**

This privacy notice explains how Kingston University ("we", "our", "us") collects, uses and shares your personal data (information) and your rights in relation to this data. The notice relates to our processing of personal data of visitors ("you", "your") to the main [Kingston University website](http://www.kingston.ac.uk/) only. This includes how we use cookies.

This privacy notice and cookie statement answers the following questions:

  * What information do we collect from our website?
  * What cookies are used on our website?
  * Who can you contact about your information?

Kingston University is the data controller of your personal data and is subject to the General Data Protection Regulation (the "GDPR") from 25 May 2018 and a new UK Data Protection Act. We may update this privacy notice periodically and if we do we will publish this on our website. The latest version of this privacy notice was updated on 18 May 2018.

For details about how we process personal information in specific use cases (for example, the personal information of enquirers, alumni and staff) and our retention schedule please refer to the information regulations section on our website.

We submit a notification of our data processing activity to the Information Commissioner's Office (ICO), specifying in general terms the classes, subjects, sources and recipients of data processed in the course of normal institutional functioning (registration number Z7456228). Our entry can be found in the online [ICO register](https://ico.org.uk/ESDWebPages/Entry/Z7456228).

## **What information do we collect from our website?**

### Information that you provide

You do not have to provide us with any personal information to access our website. However, we may ask for some personal details if you wish to access some of our services, for example:

  * To express an interest in attending open days and events (for example, via our events mailing list form);
  * To subscribe to a service (for example, to sign up to a newsletter);
  * To create a profile (for example, to register on our jobs page).

The majority of the personal information we hold about you will be obtained via our websites' online forms or if you contact us by email. What we do with this information and how long we keep it will depend on the nature of the query. We will provide information at the time that you submit it or refer to our other privacy notices for specific processing activity.

Some of the personal data that we may collect when you contact us are:

  * Biographical information (for example, your name, title, birth date, age and gender);
  * Your contact details (for example, address, email address and phone number);
  * Information about your time at the university;
  * Your professional activities;
  * Current interests and preferences;
  * Records of communications sent to you by the university or received from you;
  * Attendance at university events.

We may also process bank or credit/debit card details via third parties if you make payments via the website.

### Information that is collected automatically

In addition to personal information you may provide when you visit our website the following information is received and stored by our web servers:

  * Details of your IP address;
  * Browser type and operating system; 
  * The web pages you visited. 

This data is known as web server logs. We use this information strictly to analyse how our website is used by our visitors and we may archive this information in an anonymous form for statistical purposes.

## **What cookies are used on our website?**

Cookies are used on some parts of the Kingston University website. These are small pieces of information that are sent to and stored on your computer (unless you block them). They help us to recognise you if you return to our site at a later stage and to identify individual people in our database. Cookies cannot run programs or deliver viruses to your computer.

### **** Cookie settings

If you do not want to receive certain categories of cookies on this site, you can opt-out below.

We will still need to set a cookie so that we can remember your choices when you next visit the website from the same browser. Please note that at present it is not technically possible for us to allow you to carry your settings with you between your browsers and devices so you will need to change these settings on each browser you use.

Most web browsers allow some control of cookies through the browser settings. To find out more about cookies, including how to see what cookies have been set and how to manage and delete them, visit [All about Cookies](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/).

### 1\. Strictly necessary cookies

The PHP session cookie is strictly necessary for the functioning of our site. This cookie is used in various parts of our website to help preserve the choices you make above in a session. This cookie is deleted when you close your browser.

### 2\. Course visitor cookie

This cookie is set when viewing the course pages on our site. It allows the site to remember which courses you have viewed and added to your favourites so that these can be highlighted when you visit one of our pages.

### 3\. Google Analytics cookies

These cookies are used to collect information about how visitors use our site. We use the information to compile reports and to help us improve the site. The cookies collect information in an anonymous form, including the number of visitors to the site, where visitors have come to the site from and the pages they visited. You can find out more about [Google Analytics](http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout) and [opt out](http://www.google.co.uk/intl/en/analytics/privacyoverview.html) of being tracked across all websites. 

### 4\. Advertising cookies

We also use cookies for advertising, remarketing and retargeting purposes across all audiences, social media and web. This enables us to serve more relevant advertising as well as helping to improve our site for users. These include both Facebook and Google. Google uses cookies like NID and SID to help customise advertising on Google properties, like Google Search.

The cookies used in this process remember your most recent searches, your previous interactions with our website, search results and engagement with our advertising. This helps us to show you tailored advertising on Google based on your interests.

To opt-out from Google's remarketing programme, please edit your [Google Ad settings](https://adssettings.google.com/).

We also use cookies for advertising we produce across the web. Some of our other cookies may be used to help us assess how effective our marketing and recruitment campaigns are.

We use third-party platforms, such as DoubleClick Bid Manager to carry out our retargeting activities.

**Note:**  We do not use cookies to collect personal data unless you have opted in to receive more personalised marketing from us.

We work with [Net Natives](http://netnatives.com/privacy-policy/) and [Akero Labs](https://akerolabs.com/privacy-policy/) to deliver our advertising and you can view their privacy policies on their websites.

### 5\. Third party cookies

To support our content, we sometimes embed material from websites such as YouTube. Pages with this embedded content may present cookies from these websites. Similarly, when you use one of the share buttons on our website, a cookie may be set by the service you have chosen to share content through. Kingston University does not control the dissemination of these cookies and the share tool will not block cookies from those websites.

### More information about the cookies we use

The following cookies may be set during your visit to this site:

Cookie | Name | Purpose  
---|---|---  
Viewed and favourite courses  
| ku_course_visitor  
|  This cookie is set when viewing the course pages on our site. It allows the website to remember which courses you have viewed and added to your favourites so that these can be displayed to you when you visit one of our pages.  
PHP session  
| PHPSESSID  
|  This cookie is used in various parts of our site to help preserve the choices you make above in a session. This cookie is deleted when you close your browser.  
Google Analytics |  _utma  
_utmb  
_utmc  
_utmz  
__utmmobile |  These cookies are used to collect information about how visitors use our site. We use the information to compile reports and to help us improve the site. The cookies collect information in an anonymous form, including the number of visitors to the site, where visitors have come to the site from and the pages they visited. [Find out more.](http://www.google.co.uk/intl/en/analytics/privacyoverview.html)  
  
## **Who can you contact about your information?**

In the first instance, for details about how we process personal information in specific use cases (for example, the personal information of enquirers, alumni and staff) and our retention schedule please refer to the information regulations section on our website.

If you wish to request access to the personal data we hold about you please use the Subject Access Request Form available online. If you wish to exercise other Data Subject Rights that come under GDPR, please see the Individual Rights Request Form here. For any other queries about this privacy notice or how we process your personal data you can contact our Data Protection Officer by email: [DPO@kingston.ac.uk](mailto:DPO@kingston.ac.uk) or by post: Data Protection Officer, Vice Chancellor's Office, Crescent House, Penryhn Road, Kingston upon Thames, Surrey KT1 2EE.

If you are not satisfied with how we are processing your personal data, you can make a complaint to the Information Commissioner.

You can find out more about your rights under data protection legislation from the [Information Commissioner's Office](http://www.ico.org.uk/) website.
